A Guide to the Papers Ellen Glasgow, 1880-1963
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- CORRESPONDENCE
  - Booth Tarkington to Ellen Glasgow, 1916 Apr 14; ALS (Box 18)
  - Booth Tarkington to Ellen Glasgow, 1921 Jun 17; ALS (Box 18)
  - Booth Tarkington to Ellen Glasgow, 1940 Jul-Aug; TLS, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Allen Tate to Ellen Glasgow, 1932 Mar-Aug; ALS, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Allen Tate to Ellen Glasgow, 1932 Sep-Dec; TLS, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Allen Tate to Ellen Glasgow, 1933 Mar; TLS, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Allen Tate to Ellen Glasgow, 1933 May; TLS (Box 18)
  - Allen Tate to Ellen Glasgow, 1933 Jul 11; TLS (Box 18)
  - Allen Tate to Ellen Glasgow, 1936 Sep 22; TLS (Box 18)
  - Allen Tate to Ellen Glasgow, 1936 Dec 24; ALS (Box 18)
  - Edward Robeson Taylorto John J. Newbegin, 1915 Jun 1; ALS (Box 18)
  - Helen Taylor to Ellen Glasgow, 1940 Dec 20; TLS (Box 18)
  - H. R. Terrell to Ellen Glasgow, 1916 Sep 7; Telegram (Box 18)
  - James Thurber to Ellen Glasgow, 1942 Dec 29; TLS (Box 18)
  - Edward Larocque Tinker to Ellen Glasgow, 1932 Aug 11; ALS (Box 18)
  - Edward Larocque Tinker to Ellen Glasgow, 1932 Nov 29; TLS (Box 18)
  - Edward Laroque Tinker to Ellen Glasgow, 1942 May 5; Telegram (Box 18)
  - Olive Glasgow Titus to Ellen Glasgowenclosing "The Glasgow Family of Virginia and Ohio, 1936 Jan 17; ALS (Box 18)
  - Signe Toksvig to Ellen Glasgow, 1943 Jun-Aug; TLS, 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Signe Toksvig to Ellen Glasgow, 1943 Aug 24; APCS (Box 18)
  - Signe Toksvig to Ellen Glasgow, 1943 Sep-Dec; TLS, 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Signe Toksvig to Ellen Glasgow, 1944 Jan 9; ALS (Box 18)
  - Signe Toksvig to Ellen Glasgow, 1944 Feb; TLS, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Signe Toksvig to Ellen Glasgow, 1944 Nov 6; ALS (Box 18)
  - Signe Toksvig to Ellen Glasgow, 1944 Dec 9; TLS (Box 18)
  - Signe Toksvig to Ellen Glasgow, 1945 Jan 25; TLS (Box 18)
  - Signe Toksvig to Ellen Glasgow, 1945 Feb 3; ALS w/encl. (Box 18)
  - Signe Toksvig to Ellen Glasgow, 1945 Mar-Sep; TLS, 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Charles Hanson Towne to Ellen Glasgow, newspaper clipping (in envelope), 1932 Nov 29 (Box 18)
  - Charles Hanson Towne to Ellen Glasgow, 1938 Oct 23; TLS (Box 18)
  - Charles Hanson Towne to Ellen Glasgow, 1941 Mar 20; TLS (Box 18)
  - Charles Hanson Towne to Ellen Glasgow, 1942 May 7; ALS (Box 18)
  - Charles Hanson Towne to Ellen Glasgow, 1943 Sep 25; TLS (Box 18)
  - Ronald Tree to Ellen Glasgow, 1925 Oct 20; ALS (Box 18)
  - Amélie Rives Troubetzkoy to Ellen Glasgow, 1913 Oct 27; ALS (Box 18)
  - Amélie Rives Troubetzkoy to Ellen Glasgow, 1922 Jun 16; ALS (Box 18)
  - Amélie Rives Troubetzkoy to Ellen Glasgow, 1925 Jan; ALS, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Amélie Rives Troubetzkoy to Ellen Glasgow, 1926 Jan; ALS, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Amélie Rives Troubetzkoy to Ellen Glasgow, 1926 Dec 25; ANS (Box 18)
  - Amélie Rives Troubetzkoy to Ellen Glasgow, 1930 Feb 19; ALS (Box 18)
  - Amélie Rives Troubetzkoy to Ellen Glasgow, 1931 Feb; ALS, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Amélie Rives Troubetzkoy to Ellen Glasgow, 1931 Feb 26; ALS w/encl. Snow at Midnight (Box 18)
  - Amélie Rives Troubetzkoy to Ellen Glasgow, 1932 Sep 3; ALS w/encl. Ave Atque Vale (Box 18)
  - Amélie Rives Troubetzkoy to Ellen Glasgow, 1932 Dec 19; ALS (Box 18)
  - Amélie Rives Troubetzkoy to Ellen Glasgow, 1935 Aug-Dec; ALS, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Amélie Rives Troubetzkoy to Ellen Glasgow, 1937 Jan 3; ALS (Box 18)
  - Amélie Rives Troubetzkoy to Ellen Glasgow, 1937 Jun-Sep; ALS, 7 folders (Box 18)
  - Amélie Rives Troubetzkoy to Ellen Glasgow, 1937 Oct 6; ALS (Box 18)
  - Amélie Rives Troubetzkoy to Ellen Glasgow, 1937 Dec 26; ALS (Box 18)
  - Amélie Rives Troubetzkoy to Ellen Glasgow, 1938 Jun 8; ALS (Box 19)
  - Amélie Rives Troubetzkoy to Ellen Glasgow, 1941 Dec 20; ALS (Box 19)
  - Amélie Rives Troubetzkoy to Ellen Glasgow, 1942 Jan-Dec; ALS, 3 folders (Box 19)
  - Robert B. Tunstall to Ellen Glasgow, 1934 May 21; TLS (Box 19)
  - Robert B. Tunstall to Ellen Glasgow, 1942 May 6; Telegram (Box 19)
  - Catherine Turneyto Ellen Glasgow, 1940 Jul 16; TLS (Box 19)
  - Carrington Tutwiler to Ellen Glasgow, 1932 Jul 9; ALS (Box 19)
  - Rebe Glasgow Tutwiler to Ellen Glasgow, 1915 Oct 15; ALS (Box 19)
  - Rebe Glasgow Tutwiler to Ellen Glasgow, 1916 Nov 13; ALS (Box 19)
  - Rebe Glasgow Tutwiler to Ellen Glasgow, 1918 Sep 3; ALS (Box 19)
  - Rebe Glasgow Tutwiler to Ellen Glasgow, 1921 Feb-Dec; ALS, 5 folders (Box 19)
  - Rebe Glasgow Tutwiler to Ellen Glasgow, 1932 Oct 27; ALS (Box 19)
  - Rebe Glasgow Tutwiler to Ellen Glasgow, 1939 Feb 21; ALS (Box 19)
  - Rebe Glasgow Tutwiler to Ellen Glasgow, 1942 Dec 9; ALS (Box 19)
  - Rebe Glasgow Tutwiler to Ellen Glasgow, 1943 Apr-Feb; ALS, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Rebe Glasgow Tutwiler to Ellen Glasgow, 1945 Feb 14; ALS w/encl. (Box 19)
  - Rebe Glasgow Tutwiler to Ellen Glasgow, 1945 Mar 30; ALS (Box 19)
  - Alan Valentine to Ellen Glasgow, 1939 Feb; TLS, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Grace D. Vanamee to Ellen Glasgow, 1938 Dec 16; Telegram (Box 19)
  - Grace D. Vanamee to Ellen Glasgow, 1939 Feb; TLS, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Grace D. Vanamee to Ellen Glasgow, 1940 May 2; TLS w/autograph note (Box 19)
  - Grace D. Vanamee to Ellen Glasgow, 1940 Oct 22; TLS w/autograph note (Box 19)
  - Grace D. Vanamee to Ellen Glasgow, 1940 Dec 6; TLS (Box 19)
  - Dorothy Van Doren to Ellen Glasgow, 1932 Oct 12; TLS (Box 19)
  - Irita Van Doren to Ellen Glasgow, 1925 Mar 10; ALS (Box 19)
  - Irita Van Doren to Ellen Glasgow, 1928 Jun 5; TLS (Box 19)
  - Irita Van Doren to Ellen Glasgow, 1931 Dec 17; TLS (Box 19)
  - Irita Van Doren to Ellen Glasgow, 1933 Oct 17; TLS (Box 19)
  - Irita Van Doren to Ellen Glasgow, 1934 June; TLS, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Irita Van Doren to Ellen Glasgow, 1934 July; ALS, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Irita Van Doren to Ellen Glasgow, [1934 Aug]; TLS (Box 19)
  - Irita Van Doren to Ellen Glasgow, 1940 Sep 3; ALS (Box 19)
  - Irita Van Doren to Ellen Glasgow, 1941 Mar 19; ALS (Box 19)
  - Irita Van Doren to Ellen Glasgow, 1942 May 4; Telegram (Box 19)
  - Irita Van Doren to Ellen Glasgow, 1944 Apr-Mar; ALS, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Irita Van Doren to Frank V. Morley and Anne Virginia Bennett to Frank V. Morley, 1946 Mar; TLS (Box 19)
  - Mark Van Doren to James Branch Cabell, forwarded to Ellen Glasgow, 1925 Mar 13; TLS (Box 19)
  - Carl Van Vechten to Ellen Glasgow, 1924 Apr 9; ALS w/encl. (Box 19)
  - Carl Van Vechten to Ellen Glasgow, 1925 Apr 18; ALS (Box 19)
  - Carl Van Vechten to Ellen Glasgow, 1929 Sep; ALS, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Carl Van Vechten to Ellen Glasgow, 1932 Aug 29; ALS (Box 19)
  - Carl Van Vechten to Ellen Glasgow, 1935 Feb 6; ALS (Box 19)
  - Carl Van Vechten to Ellen Glasgow, 1938 May 11; TLS (Box 19)
  - Carl Van Vechten to Ellen Glasgow, 1941 Mar 27; TLS w/autograph note (Box 19)
  - Carl Van Vechten to Ellen Glasgow, 1942 May 5; Telegram (Box 19)
  - Carl Van Vechten to Ellen Glasgow, 1943 Sep 22; TLS (Box 19)
  - Leonie Villard to Ellen Glasgow, 1932 Sep 9; ALS (Box 19)
  - Leonie Villard to Ellen Glasgow, 1933 Sep 6; ALS (Box 19)
  - Leonie Villard to Ellen Glasgow, 1937 Mar 16; ALS (Box 19)
  - Leonie Villard to Ellen Glasgow, 1939 Dec 30; ALS (Box 19)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, 1920 Jan 25; ALS (fragment) (Box 19)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, 1920 Feb 18; ALS (Box 19)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, 1920 Apr; ALS, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, 1920 May 31; ALS (Box 19)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, 1920 Jul 23; ALS (Box 19)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, 1920 Sep 21; ALS (Box 19)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, 1920 Dec 17; ALS (Box 19)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, 1921 May 18; ALS (Box 19)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, 1921 Dec 12; ALS (Box 19)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, 1922 Jul-Sep; ALS, 3 folders (Box 19)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, 1922 Nov; ALS, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, 1922 Dec 25; ANS (Box 19)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, 1922 Dec 28; ALS (Box 19)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, 1923 Feb 8; ALS (Box 19)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, 1923 Apr 2; ALS (Box 19)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, 1923 Jun; ALS, 5 folders (Box 19)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, 1923 Aug 10; ALS (Box 19)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, 1923 Dec 18; ALS (Box 19)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, 1924 Jun 15; ALS (Box 19)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, 1924 Oct 24; ALS (Box 19)
  - Hugh Walpole to Mr. Doubleday, 1925 Jan 7; TL (copy) (Box 19)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, [1925] Dec 17; ALS (Box 19)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, 1926 Oct; ALS, 3 folders (Box 19)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, 1926 Dec; ALS, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, 1927 Feb 22; ALS (Box 20)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, 1927 Jun 17; ALS (Box 20)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, 1927 Jul; ALS, 3 folders (Box 20)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, 1929 Sep; ALS, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Hugh Walpole to Ellen Glasgow, 1930 Jan; ALS, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Virginia Watson to Ellen Glasgow, 1939 Sep 10; ALS w/encl. (Box 20)
  - Alexander Weddell to Ellen Glasgow, 1936 Jul-Sep; TLS, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Alexander Weddell to Ellen Glasgow, 1939 May 18; TLS (Box 20)
  - Alexander Weddell to Ellen Glasgow, 1940 May 23; TLS (Box 20)
  - Alexander Weddell to Ellen Glasgow, 1945 Nov 17; ALS (Box 20)
  - W. A. White to Ellen Glasgow, 1942 May 19; TLS (Box 20)
  - Wendell L. Willkie to Ellen Glasgow, 1942 May 4; Telegram (Box 20)
  - Louise Collier Wilcox to Ellen Glasgow, 1924 Mar 2; ALS (Box 20)
  - Louise Collier Wilcox to Ellen Glasgow, 1924 Aug 17; ALS (Box 20)
  - Louise Collier Wilcox to Ellen Glasgow, 1925 Apr 12; ALS (Box 20)
  - James Southall Wilson to Ellen Glasgow, 1931 Jan 10; ALS (Box 20)
  - James Southall Wilson to Ellen Glasgow, 1931 Feb 19; ALS (Box 20)
  - James Southall Wilson to Ellen Glasgow, 1931 Mar 31; ALS (Box 20)
  - James Southall Wilson to Ellen Glasgow, 1931 Oct; ALS, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - James Southall Wilson to Ellen Glasgowre Program for Southern Author's meeting at University of Virginia, 1931 Oct 13; ALS w/encl. (Box 20)
  - James Southall Wilson to Ellen Glasgow, 1931 Oct; ALS (Box 20)
  - James Southall Wilson to Ellen Glasgow, 1931 Nov 16; TLS w/encl. (Box 20)
  - James Southall Wilson to Ellen Glasgow, 1936 Aug 15; ALS (Box 20)
  - James Southall Wilson to Ellen Glasgow, 1940 Nov 23; ALS (Box 20)
  - Virginia Woolf to Ellen Glasgow, 1927 Aug 7; TLS (Box 20)
  - Edith and Katherine to Ellen Glasgow, 1942 May 5; Telegram (Box 20)
  - Katherine Woods to Ellen Glasgow, 1944 Mar 7; TLS (Box 20)
  - Francis Brett Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1921 Nov 8; TLS w/autograph note (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1925 Sep 14; ALS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1928 Dec 4; TLS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1928 Dec 20; ALS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, [1928 Dec]; TLS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1929 Jan 10; ALS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgoww/encl., 1929 Sep 18; ALS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1929 Sep; ALS, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1929 Oct-Dec; ALS, 3 folders (Box 20)
  - Stark Youngto Ellen Glasgow, 193[?] Mar 28; ALS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, [?] May 20; TLS w/autograph note (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1930 Apr 23; ALS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1930 Apr 28; ALS w/encl. (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1930 May; ALS, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1930 Jun 5; ALS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1930 Jun [5?]; ALS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1930 Jun 6; TLS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1930 Dec 1; TLS w/autograph note (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1931 Aug 24; ALS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1931 Aug 30; ALS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1931 Nov 10; ALS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1931 Nov 13; TLS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1932 Jan 11; TLS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1932 Jan 25; ALS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1932 Apr; ALS, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1932 Jul 18; TLS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1932 Aug 21; ALS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow re notes on article for National Review, 1932 Aug 26; TLSw/autograph note and encl. (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1932 Aug 30; ALS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1932 Sep 7; TLS w/autograph note (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1932 Sep 17; TLS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1933 Jan 31; TLS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1933 Feb 11; TLS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1933 Jan; ALS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1933 Feb; ALS, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1933 Mar 3; ALS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1933 Mar 29; TLS w/autograph note (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgoww/encl. and review of The Sheltered Life, 1933 May 2; ALS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1933 Jun 3; ANS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1933 Jun 13; TLS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgoww/clippings, 1933-1945 (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1933 Nov 3; ALS w/encl. (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1932 Nov 14; TLSw/autograph note (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, n.d.; ALS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1933 Jul 14; TLS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1933 Aug 13; ALS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1934 May 2; ALS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1934 Jul; ALS, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1934 Jul 25; ANS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1934 Aug 18; ALS w/encl. (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1934 Aug 31; TLS w/autograph note (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1934 Nov 18; ALS (Box 20)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1935 Apr 13; ALS (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow w/TLS from Whitney Darrow to Stark Young w/encl., ca.1935 Apr 25; ALS (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1935 May; ALS, 3 folders (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1935 Sep 2; ALS (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1936 Feb; ALS, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1936 Feb 18; ALS w/encl. (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1936 Feb; TLS, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1936 Feb 29; ALS (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1936 Mar 4; TLS (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1936 Mar; ALS, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1936 Mar 9; TLS w/autograph note (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1936 Mar; ALS, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1936 Apr 17; ALS (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgoww/TL (fragment) Allan Tate to Stark Young, 1936 Apr 24; ALS (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1936 Jul 11; ALS (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1936 Sep 29; ALS (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1936 [ ? ] 16; ALS (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1937 Apr 12; TLS w/autograph note (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1937 Apr 15; TLS w/autograph note and encl. (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1937 Apr 19; TLS w/autograph note (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1941 Jan 2; ALS (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1941 Mar 14; TLS (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1942 Nov 4; TLS w/autograph note (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1943 Sep 10; ALS (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1943 Oct; TLS, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1944 Jul 20; ALS (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1945 Apr 25; ALS (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, 1945 Aug 3; ALS (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, n.d.; TLS w/encl. (Box 21)
  - Stark Young to Ellen Glasgow, n.d.; ALS (Box 21)
  - [JJW] to Ellen Glasgow, 1939-1940; ALS (Box 21)
  - Anonymous Valentine telegrams to Ellen Glasgow, n.d.; Telegrams (Box 21)
  - B. H. to Ellen Glasgow, [ ? ] Jan [6]; ALS (Box 21)
  - Frances to Ellen Glasgow, 1935 Jul 16; ALS (Box 21)
  - Lady [Mrs. Henry S. Canby] to Ellen Glasgow, 1941 May 17; ALS (Box 21)
  - Lady [Mrs. Henry S. Canby] to Ellen Glasgow, 1943 Dec 7; APCS (Box 21)
  - Grace to Ellen Glasgow, [ ? ] Mar 23; ALS (Box 21)
  - Unknown to Ellen Glasgow, 1939-1942, n.d.; ALS, TLS (Box 21)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Mr. Wall, 1927 Oct 11; ALS (Box 21)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Maxwell E. Perkins, 1937-1938; Photocopy (Box 21)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Maxwell E. Perkins, 1937-1939; Typescripts (Box 21)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Maxwell E. Perkins- 45 letters, photocopies and typescript copies, 1937-1941 (Box 21)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Maxwell E. Perkins, photocopy negatives, 1937-1941 (Box 21)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Maxwell E. Perkins, photocopies and typescript copies (Box 21)
  - Ellen Glasgowbibliography to 1941 and clipping (Box 21)
  - Ellen Glasgowbibliography, n.d.; TMs (Box 21)
- MISCELLANEOUS
  - Bibliographical and critical Material (Box 22)
  - Family Records and Geneology - Ellen Glasgow (Box 22)
  - "Of Ellen Glasgow, " and Inscribed Portrait by Ellen Glasgowand James Branch Cabell, 1938 (Box 22)
  - The Atlantic Journal Book Supplement, containing letters between Ellen Glasgowand Marjorie Kinnan Rawlings, 1946 Apr 28 (Box 22)
  - Pearce Bailey: Gustave Flaubert: A Psychological Study (Box 22)
  - Dr. Friedrich Brie: Ellen Glasgow, TMs (Box 22)
  - Dr. Friedrich Brie: Ellen Glasgow(reprint from Germanisch-Romanischen Monatsschrift) (Box 22)
  - Christmas Cards (Box 22)
  - Jane Davenport Reid: The Ellen GlasgowCollection of Ceramic Dogs (from The Commonwealth), 1949 Feb (Box 22)
  - College of William & Mary - Citation for Doctor of Laws, 1939 Jun 5 (Box 22)
  - Coward Memory and A Battle Cry (clipping), clipping (Box 22)
  - Duke University Citation for Litt. D., 1938 Jun 6 (Box 22)
  - From A Soldier's Letter; clipping from The Ohio State Lantern, clipping (Box 22)
  - Essay on Ellen Glasgowby James Branch Cabell, n.d.; TMs (Box 22)
  - Ellen Glasgowprescriptions, 1908-1919 (Box 22)
  - Miscellaneous material re Green Forest, Glasgow family home (Box 22)
  - Albert Buerard Short Wave Broadcast re: Ellen Glasgow A Certain Measure (in French), 1943 Oct 6 (Box 22)
  - House plans and notes (Box 22)
  - Le Thyrse, containing articles on Ellen Glasgowby F. Delatte, 1934 Sep 1 (Box 22)
  - L'Oeuvre D' Ellen Glasgow, n.d.; Typescript (Box 22)
  - Maine Rural [newspaper], 1859 Feb 26 (Box 22)
  - Ellen Glasgow's Miscellaneous Pungencies (Box 22)
  - Membership Certificate in National Institute of Arts and Letters, 1932 (Box 22)
  - Pulitzer Prizes - Norfolk Ledger Dispatch editorial, 1942 May 6 (Box 22)
  - Review of The Sheltered Life, by J. Donald Adams, New York Times, 1932 Aug 28 (Box 22)
  - Revue Anglo-Americaine, containing "L'Oeuvre D' Ellen Glasgow, Romanciere Americaine" by Leonie Villardand Review of The Sheltered Life, 1933 Apr (Box 22)
  - Hubert Rouse: Studies in the Works of Ellen Glasgow, 1942 (Box 22)
  - No Place on Earth by Louis D. Rubinfrom Autumn issue "Texas Quarterly", 1959 (Box 23)
  - Materials and correspondence relating to the work of the S.P.C.A. in Richmond, Ellen Glasgow, President, 1926-1929, n. d. (Box 23)
  - The Freeman and Other Poems by Ellen Glasgow (Box 23)
  - "The New Republic", 1921 Jun 1 (Box 23)
  - Copy of "The Raven" by Edgar Allan Poe, n.d. (Box 23)
  - Invitation to join Town Hall Club, New York, sent to Ellen Glasgow, 1925 Jan 9 (Box 23)
  - Citation for Litt.D. to Ellen Glasgowfrom University of North Carolina, 1930 Jun 14 (Box 23)
  - "The Novelist As Social Scientist" by Marshall Fishwick, University of Virginia "News Letter", 1960 Aug 15 (Box 23)
  - Reviews of Frederick P. W. McDowell's book on Ellen Glasgow, " Ellen Glasgowand the Ironic Art of Fiction" (Box 23)
  - Miscellaneous clippings re Ellen Glasgow (Box 23)
  - Miscellaneous papers re Ellen Glasgow, n.d. (Box 23)
  - Glasgow clippings and reviews, 24 folders (Box 23)
  - Review, "A Prophet of the South" - New York Herald Tribune, 1929 Aug 5 (Box 24)
  - Review, In This Our Life - The [Montreal] Gazette (Box 24)
  - Clippings on 1941 Pulitzer Prize winners in The Pittsburgh Press, 1942 May 5 (Box 24)
  - Review from Savannah Morning News of The Woman Within, 1954 Oct 31 (Box 24)
  - Reviews of The Woman Within (Box 24)
  - Reviews of A Certain Measure and clippings and Galley proof of A Novelist's Faith by J. W. Krutch (Box 24)
  - English Newspaper reviews (Box 24)
  - 3 Thompson photographs re Ellen Glasgow, Photographs (Box 24)
  - Photographs used in The Woman Within, Photographs (Box 24)
  - Tan Address Book (Box 24)
  - Unidentified notes, author unknown, n.d.; AMs (Box 24)
  - 27 photographs of Ellen Glasgow, 1881-1933; Photographs, 20 folders (Box 24)
- PHOTOGRPAHS AND IMAGES
  - 53 photographs of Ellen Glasgow, 1909 & n.d.; Photographs, 24 folders (Box 25)
  - Photograph of woman sitting on rock marked "In the Valley of Virginia" - for use in Vein of Iron, n.d. (Box 25)
  - Drawing of Ellen Glasgow by S. J. Woolfwith caption promoting her novel In This Our Life, n.d.; Sketch (Box 25)
  - Watercolor of Arthur Glasgow, n.d.; Watercolor (Box 25)
  - 3 photographs of Anne Gholson Glasgow, Ellen Glasgow's mother, 1881, 1886; Photographs, 3 folders (Box 25)
  - 3 photographs of Rebe Glasgow, [1886] & 1896; Photographs, 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Photograph of Rebecca Anderson Glasgow, Ellen Glasgow's aunt (Box 25)
  - 2 photographs of Cary Glasgow, Ellen Glasgow's sister, n.d.; Photographs (Box 25)
  - Photograph of T. T. Glasgow, 1896 Sep 18 (Box 25)
  - Photograph of George Walter McCormack [Ellen Glasgow's brother-in-law], n.d. (Box 25)
  - Photograph of Frank T. Glasgow, Jr., age 5 or 6, n.d. (Box 25)
  - Photograph of Frank Glasgow at Virginia Military Institute, n.d. (Box 25)
  - Photograph of Frank Glasgow, n.d. (Box 25)
  - Photograph of Frank Y. Glasgow, n. d. (Box 25)
  - Photograph of Joseph Glasgow, n.d. (Box 25)
  - Photograph of "Uncle Will", 1886 (Box 25)
  - Photograph of Anne Virginia Bennett and two dogs (Box 25)
  - 2 photographs of Ellen Glasgow and Joseph Conrad, 1914; Photographs (Box 25)
  - Photograph of Mr. [?] Paradise, n.d. (Box 25)
  - Photograph of portrait of Elizabeth Bronte, n.d. (Box 25)
  - Photograph of Gertrude Stein, n.d. (Box 25)
  - 2 photographs of Ellen Glasgow and Joseph Conrad with unidentified man and woman (Box 25)
  - Photograph by Carl Van Vechten of a dog in a chair, 1935 (Box 25)
  - Photograph by Carl Van Vechten of stone steps with urns, 1936 Feb 7 (Box 25)
  - Photograph of unidentified woman [believed to be a relative of Ellen Glasgow], n.d. (Box 25)
  - Drawing of an unidentified man [believed to be a relative of Ellen Glasgow], n.d. (Box 25)
  - Sketch of a man entitled The Major, n.d. (Box 25)
  - Sketch of woman Virginia by Granville Smith, n.d. (Box 25)
  - Photograph of Jerdone Castle, after fifty years of neglect, n.d. (Box 25)
  - Photo of Old Mill, n.d. (Box 25)
  - Photograph of front of Glasgow house in Richmond (Box 25)
  - Photograph of yard from porch [Glasgow house in Richmond] (Box 25)
  - 6 sketches of the southern gallery of Ellen Glasgow's house, n.d. (Box 26)
  - 7 photographs of various rooms in the Glasgow house, n.d. (Box 26)
  - 6 photographs of one corner of back porch and yard of Ellen Glasgow's house with "Jeremy" headstone (Box 26)
  - Photograph of headstone inscribed "Jeremy", 1935 (Box 26)
  - Photograph of garden with "Jeremy" headstone, [rear of Glasgow house], n.d. (Box 26)
  - Photograph of front of a house marked Tebbs and Knell, New York (Box 26)
  - Photograph of Linden Row in Richmond (Box 26)